Finding Aid for Arthur J. Tuttle Papers 1849-1958
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Arthur J. Tuttle Papers 1849-1958 1888-1944
Tuttle, Arthur J., 1868-1944.
U.S. District Court Judge, Eastern District of Michigan; Federal trial court case files, personal and professional correspondence, scrapbooks, University of Michigan student notebooks, and other materials concerning legal activities, Republican Party politics, prohibition, the election of 1924, Sigma Alpha Epsilon affairs; also family materials, including grandfather, John J. Tuttle, Leslie, Michigan, Ingham County official and businessman; and photographs.
86134 Aa 2; UAm; UAx
108 linear feet
1 oversize folders
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The major portion of the collection was received in several accessions between 1945 and 1958 from Arthur Tuttle's daughters, Mrs. Thomas H. Bailey and Mrs. H. Blair Freeman (Donor No. 2104 ). Additional materials were received in three accessions in 1958, 1965, and 1985, from Mrs. Tuttle Bailey (Donor No. 3407 ).
The collection is open for research.
Arthur J. Tuttle was born on a farm in Leslie, Michigan, on November 8, 1868, to Ogden Valorius and Julia Elizabeth (McArthur) Tuttle. His grandfather, John J. Tuttle, settled in southern Michigan in 1837, establishing a farm. John Tuttle became a prominent citizen of Ingham County, serving as County Coroner, Justice of the Peace, School Director and Leslie Township Supervisor.
Arthur entered the University of Michigan and graduated with a Ph.B in 1892. He then enrolled in the university's law school and obtained a Bachelor of Laws Degree in 1895. Tuttle joined forty-four fraternal, civic, benevolent, law and scholastic organizations throughout his collegiate and professional life. Among them were: Phi Beta Kappa, Phi Alpha Delta, American and Detroit Bar Associations, Council of American Law Institute, Michigan State Horticultural Society, Detroit Boat Club, Detroit Athletic Club, Detroit Golf Club, Detroit Automotive Club and Rotary Club. For many years he served as bank president for the People's Bank of Leslie and director of the Home Telephone Company.
Tuttle's public life began with his election as Prosecuting Attorney of Ingham County in 1898. Here he gained notoriety for his dogged grand jury investigation of graft in connection with a military board that equipped troops during the Spanish-American War. Tuttle even had a subpoena served on governor Hazen S. Pingree while he was rushing for a train out of Lansing. Two brigadier generals were convicted, but received unconditional pardons from an angry Governor.
On March 11, 1903, Tuttle married Jessie Beatrice Stewart of Harsen's Island. The newlyweds honeymooned in Europe. Jessie gave birth to a daughter, Ruth, in March of 1904 and a second daughter, Esther, in September, 1905. In 1907, he joined the Lansing law firm of McArthur & Dunnebacke, becoming a senior partner. That same year he took a seat in the Michigan State Senate after being elected from the 14th district. He served in Michigan's Senate until 1910. In 1911 President William Howard Taft appointed him U.S. District Attorney for the Eastern District of Michigan. In 1912 he became the federal judge for the eastern district of Michigan.
As congratulatory letters were arriving, Jessie died unexpectedly on August 24th, only twelve days after he was sworn in. She was thirty-four. He never remarried, and raised his two daughters alone. Some of his happiest moments came when his daughters, Ruth and Esther, were admitted to the bar in 1930 after graduating from law school at the University of Michigan, and when they wed in a double ceremony in 1936.
Splitting his time between courtrooms in Detroit and Bay City, the Judge toiled diligently with the backlog of cases left by Judge Alexis Caswell Angell, winning respect for his hard work and dedication. It would be ten years before Congress would create another judgeship in the district to alleviate an ever-burgeoning workload. During that time Tuttle gained a reputation as a stern judge, especially in the sentencing of "white slavers" who through the prostitution trade had violated the federal Mann Act.
Prohibition unleashed a new wave of crime and in 1924 Tuttle sentenced Hamtramck Mayor Peter C. Jezewski, together with the city's former police commissioner and a former police lieutenant, to two years in Leavenworth for their role in a "beer ring". He was lenient on the saloonkeepers, however, saying, "conspiracy with the brain is more culpable than conspiracy with the hands."
When the overworked judge had time off, he would retreat to his family's 160-acre apple farm in Leslie. He was an avid hunter. Deer season often took him to northern Michigan, and his private judicial chambers were filled with trophy mounts.
In 1924, Tuttle and three others -- Republicans Hal H. Smith, Daniel W. Tussing, and Democrat Mortimer E. Cooley -- challenged U.S. Senator James Couzens in the September 9th primary. Tuttle was considered the strongest challenger. Tuttle had the backing of farmers and temperance groups and the endorsement of the Detroit Free Press while Couzens enjoyed the support of labor. Tuttle carried the out-state vote by a close margin, but lost in Detroit where Couzens defeated him by better than 2-1.
Back on the bench, Tuttle continued to work conscientiously. In his first twenty years of service, he was reversed only 35 times. He gained a reputation within the federal judiciary as an expert in patent and admiralty law. In 1927 he presided over hearings in the famous one-million-dollar libel suit brought against auto industrialist Henry Ford by Aaron Sapiro, a leader in the nation's farm cooperative movement. However, after a few months he recused himself upon being charged with bias by Ford's lawyers.
The two biggest and most controversial cases in Tuttle's 32 years on the federal bench came later in his tenure. On November 30, 1937, following the directive of a jury, Tuttle sentenced 38-year-old Polish immigrant Anthony Chebatoris to hang. A career criminal, Chebatoris shot an innocent bystander during a foiled bank robbery in Midland, Michigan. In 1846, Michigan had been the first English-speaking government in the world to abolish capital punishment for murder. State law, however, did not apply because the defendant had violated the National Bank Robbery Act of 1934.
The hanging of Chebatoris at the federal prison in Milan would be the only execution ever to take place within Michigan borders since statehood in 1837. Chebatoris was hanged in Milan at dawn on July 8, 1938. Governor Murphy called it "a blot on Michigan's civilized record."
In 1942, during another high-profile case, Judge Tuttle sentenced German-born Max Stephan, a Detroit restaurant owner, to hang for assisting a Nazi pilot who had escaped a Canadian prisoner-of-war camp. Lieutenant Hans Peter Krug contacted Stephan after crossing the Detroit River in a rowboat. Stephan gave him drinks, food, lodging and the services of a prostitute before paying his bus fare to Chicago. Krug, who was captured in San Antonio on his way to Mexico, testified against Stephan. Stephan was convicted by a jury on July 2, 1942.
The sentence surprised the packed courtroom of several hundred people. Few had expected a penalty of death. Stephan became the first person in the country convicted of treason since the Whiskey Rebellion of 1794. The U.S. Supreme Court refused to intervene three separate times. President Roosevelt., on July 1st, less than twelve hours before the traitor's date with death, commuted the death sentence to life imprisonment. The President stated that Stephan had been "properly convicted of treason," but that death was too harsh a punishment.
Arthur J. Tuttle had served the federal judiciary for 32 years when he took ill in late 1944. Tuttle died at Henry Ford Hospital in Detroit December 3rd at age 76. Judge Tuttle was buried at Woodlawn Cemetery in his native Leslie, Michigan. Hal H. Smith, described Judge Tuttle in an eloquent tribute on behalf of the Detroit Bar Association: "He had what I call a mental integrity, a conscience of the mind. The rule that governed him was his respect for the law as supreme arbiter. He had intense political and social convictions, but when the law and the statute did not square with them, he sternly repressed those convictions. He never let his judgments be swayed by them or his prejudice.
(The above sketch was adapted from "Arthur J. Tuttle: Dean of the Federal Bench" by Aaron J. Veselenak in The Court Legacy Newsletter, April, 1999, published by the Historical Society United States District Court of the Eastern District of Michigan. http://www.mied.uscourts.gov/_historical/newspdf/apr99.pdf)
The Arthur J. Tuttle Papers are arranged in 13 series: case files, opinions and jury instructions, topical office files, conciliation commissioners, criminal files, correspondence, letterbooks, scrapbooks, University of Michigan, financial matters, miscellaneous biographical materials, Tuttle family materials, and visual materials.
Subjects:
Elections--Michigan--1924.; Ingham County (Mich.); Judges--Michigan.; Law.; Leslie (Mich.); Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.; Michigan--Politics and government--1899-1916.; Michigan--Politics and government--1917-1921.; Michigan--Politics and government--1922-1928.; Michigan--Politics and government--1929-1938.; Michigan--Politics and government--1939-1945.; Prohibition--Michigan.; Republican Party (Mich.); Sigma Alpha Epsilon.; Tuttle, Arthur J., 1868-1944.; University of Michigan--Student notebooks.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Agriculture.; Banks--Michigan--Leslie.; Cabins.; Camp Bryn Afon (Rhinelander, Wis.); Camps--1921-1930.; Canoes.; Celebrations.; Children.; Cigars.; Dwellings.; Families.; Farms.; Fish.; Floods.; Grand River (Mich.); Horeseback riding.; Hunting--United States.; Interiors.; Judges--Michigan.; Lawyers--Michigan.; Leslie (Mich.); Leslie (Mich.)--Banks.; Leslie (Mich.)--Tornadoes--1916.; Lyons (Mich.); Michigan. Legislature.; Monuments and memorials.; Offices.; Orchards.; People's Bank of Leslie.; Photographers.; Pleasant Lake (Jackson County, Mich.); Political elections--1896.; Rites and ceremonies.; Rural schools.; Stuart family.; Swimming.; Tintypes.; Tornadoes--Michigan--Leslie--1916.; Tuttle, Arthur J., 1868-1944.; Tuttle, John J., b. 1812.; Tuttle, Ogden Valorous, 1842-1916.; Tuttle family.; Uniforms.; University of Michigan. Class of 1892.; Women.; Women--Work.
Contributors:
Tuttle, John J., b. 1812.
Genre/Form:
Albums.; Ambrotypes.; Daguerreotypes.; Diaries.; Drawings.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Case Files
  The Case files series (17 linear feet) dates from Tuttle's appointment to the Federal Bench in 1912 through his death in 1944 and consist of the files he kept in chambers about matters pending before him. These are not the court clerk's files, but are rather the judge's correspondence with attorneys, briefs, pleadings, opinions and other materials about the cases to which he required easy access. Some files contain transcripts of court hearings and have been so designated in the box listing. This series contains primarily civil cases, but there are also a few criminal cases. Files which substantially duplicated materials kept in the court clerk's files, or which related to routine matters such as uncomplicated bankruptcies were not retained, although all opinions written by Tuttle were retained and placed in the "Opinions and jury instructions" series. The files are arranged in chronological sequences according to the date the case was closed (not filed).
  - 1912-1917
    - Alabama & New Orleans Trans. Co. v. Edward H. Doyle et al. (Box 1)
      (Blue Sky Law, per curiam)
    - American Voiturette Co., Bankrupt (Box 1)
    - Carl Arfa, Habeas Corpus (Russian Alien) (Box 1)
    - Isa McBean Bindley v. Detroit River Tunnel Co. et al. (Box 1)
    - Blue Sky Law: N.W. Halsey v. F.W. Merrick et al., The Weis Fibre Container Corp. v. F.W. Merrick et al. (Box 1)
    - Philip Bommorito v. Yellow Taxicab Co. (Box 1)
    - Buffalo Steamship Co. v. Steamer "Stephen Clement" (Box 1)
      (Includes transcript)
    - Cambria Steel Co. v. Steamer "Benjamin Noble" (Box 1)
    - Capac Paper Co., Bankrupt (Box 1)
    - James D. Carey v. Detroit Iron and Steel Co. (Box 1)
    - Dora B. Clark (Oxford Mercantile Co.), Bankrupt (Box 1)
    - Coca-Cola Co. v. McBride et al. (Box 1)
    - Continental Securities Co. v. New York Central RR. (Box 1)
    - Detroit & Mackinac Ry. Co. v. Michigan RR Commn. et al. (Box 1)
    - Eugene G. Donohoe, Trustee of American Silica Co. v. Joseph W. Dykstra et al. (Box 1)
    - Flanders Mfg. Co., Bankrupt (Box 1)
      (Electric Automobiles)
    - Hyman L. Goldman v Maurice Goldberger (Box 1)
    - Grand Island Steamship Co. v. Steamer "Wahcondah" (Box 1)
    - Harrell & Nicholson Co., Bankrupt (Box 1)
    - Henry P. Hill, Bankrupt (Box 1)
    - Hyman Kaplan, Bankrupt (Box 1)
    - Kawneer Mfg. Co. v. Detroit Show Case Co. (Box 1)
    - Kawneer Mfg. Co. v. Toledo Plate & Window Glass Co. (Box 1)
      (Correspondence with West Publishing Co. regarding publishing oral decisions)
    - Lam Fung Yen, Habeas Corpus (Box 1)
      (Chinese immigrant)
    - Harmon L. Keidan, Bankrupt (Box 1)
    - Lozier Motor Co., Bankrupt (Box 1)
    - Manufacturer's Wholesale Furniture Co., Bankrupt (Box 1)
    - Herbert W. Merrill, Habeas Corpus (Box 1)
    - Gilbert E. Miller v. Prudential Casualty Co. (Box 1)
    - George N. Monroe, Bankrupt (Box 1)
    - National Home & Hotel Supply Co., Bankrupt (Box 1)
    - Niagara Transit Co. v. Tug "Security" and Standard Oil Barge No. 96 (Box 1)
    - Millard D. Olds v. Herman H. Hettler Lumber Co. (Box 2)
    - Louis E. O'Neil v. Oscar L. McKinley (Box 2)
    - Parsons Non-Skid Co., Ltd. v. Perry Chain Grip Co., et al. (Box 2)
      (Tire tread patent)
    - James Paul, Bankrupt (Box 2)
    - Charles Perna v. Rapid Ry. Co. (Box 2)
    - Philadelphia Casualty Co. v. Henry H. Fechheimer, et al. (Box 2)
      (Circuit Court Appeals)
    - R-C-H. Corp., Bankrupt (Box 2)
    - J.S. Rawlings v. Omega Separator Co. (Box 2)
    - Republic Motor Truck Co. v. Pittsburgh Model Engine Co. (Box 2)
    - Richards Bros., Bankrupts (Box 2)
    - William Sauer v. Detroit Times Corp. (Box 2)
      (Includes transcript, copyright of maps)
    - Thomas Sayres v. Steamer "Hamonic" and v. Detroit Ship Building Co. (Box 2)
    - John H. Sears v. City of Akron (Box 2)
    - State Bank of Chicago v. Churchill Lumber Co. (Box 2)
    - Maurice Sugar, et al, Habeas Corpus (Box 2)
      (Congressman Clare Hoffman)
    - Rowe Tysen v. Fay L. Hand (Box 2)
    - U.S. v. Grand Rapids & Indiana Ry (Box 2)
    - U.S. v. Kellogg Toasted Corn Flakes Co. (Box 2)
      (per curiam)
    - U.S. v. Lem Gow (Box 2)
    - U.S. v. Thomas McCoo (Box 2)
      (Mann Act)
    - Warren Motor Car Co., Bankrupt. (Box 2)
    - Tony Wierzbicky, Habeas Corpus (Box 2)
    - Williams Bros., Bankrupts (Box 2)
      (Pickles and preserves)
  - 1918-1920
    - American Can Co. v. Mulkey Salt Co. (Box 3)
    - American Distributing Co. v. Hayes Wheel Co. (Box 3)
    - American Steel Supply Syndicate, Bankrupt (Box 3)
    - Julius Bonk, Bankrupt (Box 3)
    - Continental Securities Co. v. Michigan Central RR Co. (Box 3)
    - Detroit, Toledo & Ironton Ry. Co., Bankrupt (Box 3)
    - Detroit United Ry. v. City of Detroit (Box 3)
    - Henry Ford v. Truman E. Newberry (Box 3)
      (Ballot boxes)
    - Fremont Lumber Co., Bankrupt and In re Professional Standing of Hal C. DeRan (Box 3)
      (Ohio)
    - Walter Goodwin, Habeas Corpus (Box 3)
      (Military Draft)
    - Longley v. Capital Transportation Co. (Box 3)
      (Admiralty)
    - Michigan Power Co., Bankrupt
      - Valuation Report of Prof. M.E. Cooley 1911, 1918 (Box 3)
        Appraisal, with photos of buildings
      - Receiver's Inventory of Property 1918 (Box 3)
      - Cash Reports (Box 3)
      - Correspondence and Pleadings I (Box 3)
      - Correspondence and Pleadings II (Box 3)
    - Michigan Ry. Co. v. City of Lansing (Box 3)
    - Peninsular Portland Cement Co. v. Consolidation Coal Co., 2 folders (Box 3)
    - St. Clair Paper Co., Bankrupt (Box 3)
      (Folder 1 of 2)
    - St. Clair Paper Co., Bankrupt (Box 4)
      (Folder 2 of 2)
    - U.S. v. Grant Hugh Browne (Box 4)
      (Army graft)
    - U.S. v. Fred Gabriel (Box 4)
      (Includes transcript, counterfeiting)
    - U.S. v. Louis Jasik (Box 4)
      (Threatened the president, sedition)
    - U.S. v. Ralph S. Windhorst (Box 4)
      (Conspiracy to defraud the army)
    - Isaac Wiener, Trustee v. Frank B. Hibbler (Box 4)
  - 1921-1923
    - Acme White Lead and Color Works v. Republican Motor Truck Co. (Box 4)
    - Dayton, Toledo & Chicago Ry. Co., Bankrupt, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Detroit, Bay City & Western Ry. Co., Bankrupt (Box 4)
      (Includes blueprint map of RR line)
    - Detroit & Toledo Shore Line Ry. v. Detroit, Toledo & Ironton Ry. (Box 4)
    - Detroit & Mackinac Ry. Co. v. Boyne City, Gaylord & Alpena Ry Co. (Box 4)
    - Detroit, Toledo & Chicago Ry. Co., Bankrupt (Box 4)
    - Drugcraft Co., Bankrupt (Box 4)
    - Louis Epstein, Bankrupt (Box 4)
    - Gerard-Summers Co., Bankrupt (Box 4)
    - Walter B. Grant, Executor of Albert W. Brown v. Frank W. Fletcher (Box 4)
    - Hamtramck Conspiracy Case (Box 4)
      (Judge's guide to defendants and witnesses)
    - Charles R. Hannan, Jr. v. Matthew Slush, et al. (Box 4)
      (Contains a photo of bank checks)
    - Thomas Henderson, Bankrupt (Box 4)
    - Home Beverage Co. (Box 4)
      (Indictment of grand jury)
    - Webb Jay v. Ireland & Matthews Mfg. Co. (Box 4)
      (Carburetor patent)
    - Joseph Kerekes, Habeas Corpus (Box 4)
    - Liberty Highway v. Michigan Public Utilities Co. (Box 4)
      (Correspondence with Judge Donohue of 6th Circuit)
    - Lincoln Motor Car Co., Bankrupt (Box 4)
    - Maxwell Motor Co., Inc., Bankrupt (Box 4)
    - Michigan Central RR Co. v. Michigan Public Utilities Comm'n. and Security Mortgage Corp. v Michigan Securities Comm'n (Box 4)
    - Michigan Motor Specialties Co., Bankrupt (Box 4)
      (Contains original court exhibit of a patent)
    - Michigan State Telephone Co. v. Samuel Odell (Box 4)
      (Letter from Detroit Mayor James Couzens)
    - Merrill A. Moss, Bankrupt (Box 4)
      (Six page letter by AJT explaining and criticizing bankruptcy system)
    - Natow Bros., Bankrupt (Box 4)
    - Pere Marquette Ry. Co. v. John C. Roderisk, et al (Box 5)
      (Strike injunction. Includes transcript, newspaper clippings)
    - Republic Acceptance Corp. v. Charles J. DeLand, 2 folders (Box 5)
      (Michigan's corporate franchise tax unconstitutional, correspondence with Merlin Wiley, Michigan Attorney General)
    - River Rouge Condemnation Case, 7 folders (Box 5)
      (Important parties include Ford Motor Co., U.S. Attorney Earl J. Davis, Dodge Bros., American Agricultural Chemical Co., Dunbar & Sullivan Dredging Co., Detroit, Toledo and Ironton RR. Contains blueprint map of River Rouge area; AJT's long letter to Attorney General H.M. Daugherty outlining unfair condemnation proceedings, transcript of examinations of expert witnesses as to valuation and damage to property.)
    - Saxon Motor Car Co., Bankrupt (Box 5)
      (Includes discussion of auction procedures in a sale of assets.)
    - Union Motor Truck Co., Bankrupt (Box 5)
    - U.S. v. Burroughs Adding Machine Co., Moon-Hopkins Billing Machine, Intervenors U.S. v. Carl J. Lankenau, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Vassar Foundry Co., Bankrupt (Box 5)
    - Bryant Walker v. John A. Grogan, Collector IRS (Box 5)
      (Estate tax)
  - 1924-1925
    - Ann Arbor Machine Corp., Bankrupt (Box 5)
    - U.S. v. Frank Cardigan, et al. (Box 5)
      (Car theft ring, Dyer Act)
    - U.S. v. Edwin R. Cornish (Box 5)
      (Editor of Worker's Voice criticized Tuttle's ruling in Pere Marquette strike. Tuttle held him in contempt. Case was appealed and 6th Circuit chastised Tuttle)
    - Circuit Court of Appeals Cases
      (Correspondence with Circuit Court Judges Maurice H. Donahue of Columbus, Ohio, Charles H. Moorman of Louisville, Kentucky)
      - Miscellaneous Matters (Box 5)
      - Cadillac Co. v. U.S. (Box 5)
      - C.G. Cate v. U.S. (Box 5)
      - John J. Gozner v. U.S. (Box 5)
        (Includes transcript, Tuttle drafted opinion)
      - John W. Hansel v. Benjamin Franklin Purnell and Israelite House of David (Box 6)
        (Religious cult)
      - Hocking Valley Ry. Co. v. Van B. Whitaker (Box 6)
      - R.B. Levi v. U.S. (Box 6)
        (War risk insurance)
      - U.S. v. Louisville & Jeffersonville Bridge & RR Co. (Box 6)
      - Rosario Maccieno v. U.S. (Box 6)
        (Search warrant)
      - McBryde v. U.S. (Box 6)
      - Patrick McGinty v. Penn. RR Co. (Box 6)
      - Philip Miller v. U.S. (Box 6)
      - National Surety Co. v. Brown-Graves (Box 6)
      - J.W. Simmons v. U.S. (Box 6)
    - Detroit Bay City & Western Ry. Bankrupt, 4 folders (Box 6)
    - Louis J. Epstein, Bankrupt (Box 6)
    - U.S. v. Guy Forward and William Bates (Box 6)
      (Narcotics, includes transcript)
    - Gear Grinding Machine Co. v. Reo Motor Car Co. (Box 6)
    - Gleaner Clearing House Assn., Bankrupt (Box 6)
    - Mae E. Gouthro, Habeas Corpus (Box 6)
    - U.S. v. P. Koenig Coal Co. (Box 6)
    - Stroh Products Co. v. James R. Davis (Box 6)
      (Prohibition)
    - Thunder Bay Limestone Co. v. Detroit & Mackinac Ry. Co. (Box 6)
    - U.S. v. Traugott Schmidt & Sons (Box 6)
      (World War I procurement fraud)
    - Alpha S. Whitehead, Bankrupt (Box 6)
  - 1926-June, 1929
    - American Plug Co. et al v. Hudson Motor Car Co. (Box 6)
      (Patent)
    - American Vitrified Products Co. v. Mill Owners' Mutual Fire Insurance (Box 6)
    - U.S. v. Harry Cardwell (Box 6)
      (Smuggling whiskey)
    - Circuit Court of Appeals
      (Correspondence with Judges Maurice H. Donohue of Columbus, Ohio, Charles H. Moorman, of Louisville, Ky., Arthur C. Denison, Grand Rapids, Mich., Smith Hickenlooper, Cincinnati, Ohio)
      - John B. Allen v. U.S. (Box 6)
        (Liquor)
      - Bassick Mfg. Co. v. Larkin A. P. Co. and O.K. Mfg. Co. (Box 6)
      - George Hardwig v. U.S. (Box 6)
        (Search and seizure of still)
      - Fred W. King (Box 6)
        (Fraud)
      - Anthony McCarthy and John Cody v. U.S. (Box 6)
      - Mike Maichok v. Bertha-Consumers Co. (Box 6)
        (Miner's injuries)
      - Samuel J. Schneider, trustee v. Springman (Box 6)
        (Bankruptcy)
      - Stewart E. Seaman v. Southern Cotton & Paper Co. (Box 6)
        (Bankruptcy, Tuttle drafted opinion)
      - Texas Co. v. M. M. Brice (Box 6)
        (Wrongful death, Tuttle drafted opinion)
      - John Van Range Co. v. William Meade (Box 6)
      - J. Harry Wiener v. Harry H. Weiss, Collector IRS (Box 6)
        (Taxation)
    - J. McNair Ealy, et al, Bankrupt (Box 6)
    - William S. Ferguson v. Detroit Railway & Harbor Terminals Co., 4 folders (Box 6)
      (Steel girder patent, includes transcript)
    - Grand Trunk Ry Co. of Canada v. Detroit & Toledo Shore Line RR (Box 7)
    - Haynes Stellite Co. v. Chesterfield (Box 7)
      (Patent, includes 3 graph and photo exhibits)
    - Haynes Stellite Co., 4 volumes contains exhibits (Box 7)
    - Roscoe C. Hoffman v. Motor Wheel Corp., 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Kirkpatrick v. Barry (Box 7)
    - U.S. v. Isadore Luvisch et al. (Box 7)
      (Counterfeiting)
    - Masonic Country Club of Western Michigan v. Charles Holden, Collector IRS (Box 7)
    - Monroe Gas Light and Fuel Co., v. Michigan Public Utilities Comm'n, 2 folders (Box 7)
      (Injunction, gas rates, Judge Arthur Denison)
    - Motor Improvements Inc. v. General Motors (Box 7)
    - Nature's Rival v. Jackson Corset Co., 4 folders (Box 7)